Fiber Flightcheck
Know whether a Fiber payment can succeed before sending it.
A running Fiber node can still fail at payment time.
Flightcheck checks node, channel, funding, asset, and liquidity state first.
Start with a real request: can this node send 10 CKB now?
The app server queries its private FNN RPC.
The browser never receives or selects that endpoint.
One result combines network health, synchronization, peers,
channels, asset support, and directional capacity.
ChannelReady confirms lifecycle state.
Sendable and receivable balances are evaluated separately.
On-chain CKB funding and off-chain channel liquidity answer
different operational questions, so Flightcheck reports both.
Payment Proof runs a real server-side keysend dry run
against an operator-configured Fiber peer.
The public proof is amount-capped, cooldown-limited, target-restricted,
and redacted. Live payment execution remains locked.
Every check can produce auditable Markdown, JSON, or PDF evidence.
The same structured result is reusable from the UI, CLI, API, or CI.
Scenario Lab regression-tests known failure states
without disrupting the live Fiber node.
Simulated scenarios are clearly separated from
the live readiness and payment-proof paths.
Live Fiber state. One readiness decision. One next action.
github.com/Jayrodri088/fiber-flightcheck